<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<binary>
<name>geo_smergefb</name>
<location>src.bin/imagery/graphic/geo_smergefb</location>
<syntax>geo_smergefb --help</syntax>
<syntax>geo_smergefb [<ar>options</ar>] <ar>filename</ar></syntax>
<syntax>geo_smergefb -ppm [<ar>options</ar>] <ar>filename</ar></syntax>
<syntax>geo_smergefb -ppmx [<ar>options</ar>] <ar>filename</ar></syntax>
<syntax>geo_smergefb -xml [<ar>options</ar>] <ar>filename</ar></syntax>


<option><on>--help</on><od>print the help message and exit.</od>
</option>

<option><on>-cf <ar>cfname</ar></on><od>read command line options from the file <ar>cfname</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-wdt <ar>width</ar></on><od>set the width of the plot to <ar>width</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-hgt <ar>height</ar></on><od>set the height of the plot to <ar>height</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-sf <ar>scale</ar></on><od>set the scale factor (magnification) to <ar>scale</ar>. The default scale factor is 1.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-ortho</on><od>use an orthographic projection.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-stereo</on><od>use a stereographic projection.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-gvp</on><od>use a general vertical projection.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-lat <ar>lat</ar></on><od>center the plot on the latitude given by <ar>lat</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-lon <ar>lon</ar></on><od>center the plot on the longitude given by <ar>lon</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-latmin <ar>latmin</ar></on><od>adjust the scale factor so that the lowest visible latitude is  <ar>latmin</ar>. Applies when the stereographic projection is used.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-mag</on><od>use magnetic coordinates.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-rotate</on><od>rotate the plot so that the local noon is at the top of the plot.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-flip</on><od>flip the direction of the X-axis.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-square</on><od>force the use of a square bounding box around the plot.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-lst</on><od>use local solar time rather than local time.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-tf <ar>factor</ar></on><od>Set the transparency factor to <ar>factor</ar>. The transparency factor controls how the alpha channel of the image. A ratio is calculated using the equation (1-<ar>factor</ar>)+<ar>c</ar>*<ar>factor</ar>, where <ar>c</ar> is the intensity of the pixel in the satellite image. This ratio is then used to calculate the alpha channel component of the pixel.</od>
</option>




<option><on>-d <ar>yyyymmdd</ar></on><od>plot for the date <ar>yyyymmdd</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-t <ar>hr:mn</ar></on><od>plot for the time <ar>hr:mn</ar>.</od>
</option>

<option><on>-inx <ar>color</ar></on><od>for a multi-color image, plot the color channel <ar>color</ar>.</od>
</option>

<option><on>-key <ar>keyname</ar></on><od>load the color bar from the file <ar>vkeyname</ar>.</od>
</option>

<option><on>-min <ar>min</ar></on><od>set the minium value of the intensity scale to <ar>min</ar>.</od>
</option>

<option><on>-max <ar>max</ar></on><od>set the maximum value of the intensity scale to <ar>max</ar>.</od>
</option>

<option><on>-log</on><od>use a logarithmic scale.</od>
</option>


<option><on>-stretch</on><od>Use the full range of the color bar. By default the the color bar ranges from zero to the maximum intensity.</od>
</option>

<option><on>-name <ar>name</ar></on><od>assign the name <ar>name</ar> to the bitmap. This is used by those image formats that support named images (PPMX,XML).</od>
</option>

<option><on>-ppm</on><od>produce a Portable PixMap (PPM) image as the output.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-ppmx</on><od>produce an extended Portable PixMap (PPMX) image as the output.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-xml</on><od>produce an XML image representation as the output.</od>
</option>

<option><on><ar>filename</ar></on><od>filename of the sImage filename table.</od></option>


<synopsis><p>Plot an image formed by interpolating between sImage files.</p></synopsis>

<description><p>Plot an image formed by interpolating between sImage files.</p>
<p>The names of the satellite image files are stored in the table supplied as the filename on the command line. This plain ASCII file has the following format:</p>

<quote><em>syr smo sdy shr smn ssc eyr emo edy ehr emn esc filename</em></quote>
<p>Where <em>syr, smo, sdy, shr, smn, ssc</em> give the start date and time of the sImage file, <em>eyr, emo, edy, ehr, emn, esc</em> give the end date and time, and <em>filename</em> is the name of the sImage file.</p>
<p>The program locates the two sImage files that bracket the time given on the command line and performs a simple linear interpolation of the two images to produce the output image.</p>
<p>The output can be to an X terminal, XML rplot file, Portable PixMap (PPM) file, extended Portable PixMap (PPMX) file, or PostScript file. The default output is XML.</p>

<p>The default map projection is a simple cylindrical projection, the most useful projection is the stereographic projection invoked using the "<code>-stereo</code>" option.</p>

<p>The number and complexity of the command line options makes typing them a laborious process, especially when producing multiple plots. To solve this problem, command line options can be placed in plain text file that can be parsed by the program using the " <code>-cf</code>" option. This allows the user to create a set of configuration files for producing different plots.</p> 

</decription>
<example>
<command>geo_smergefb -ppm -wdt 540 -hgt 540 -lon -130  -lat 20 -min 10 -max 60 -stretch -ortho -key vis.key -d 20021220 -t 23:38:53 vis.time.txt &gt; fg.ppm</command>
<description>Plot the interpolated satellite image found using the filename lookup table "<code>vis.time.txt</code>" and the date of 20th December, 2002 and time of 23:38:53UT.
</description>
</example>

<example type="image">example1</example>


</binary>